<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hao Zhu</title>
    <link>https://zhuhao.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hao Zhu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zhuhao.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Gaussian Process in Python and R</title>
      <link>https://zhuhao.org/post/gp_python_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhuhao.org/post/gp_python_r/</guid>
      <description>library(reticulate) reticulate::use_condaenv(&amp;quot;dl&amp;quot;) knitr::opts_chunk$set(message = F, warning = F) This blog post is trying to implementing Gaussian Process (GP) in both Python and R. The main purpose is for my personal practice and hopefully it can also be a reference for future me and other people. In fact, it’s actually converted from my first homework in a Bayesian Deep Learning class.
A interesting finding is that the implementation in R is much faster than the one using numpy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting R and arduino wirelessly through websockets</title>
      <link>https://zhuhao.org/post/connecting-r-and-arduino-through-websockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhuhao.org/post/connecting-r-and-arduino-through-websockets/</guid>
      <description>In the last post, I demonstrated how to send data from arduino to R through serial connection. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about how to connect R and arduino through wireless websocket connection. Trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s not as hard as it sounds like.
Hardware requirements Obviously, you need an arduino board that can connect to the Internet. Today, the most popular boards of this kind includes ESP8266 or ESP32.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on designing hex stickers for #rstats packages</title>
      <link>https://zhuhao.org/post/tips-on-designing-a-hex-sticker-for-rstats-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhuhao.org/post/tips-on-designing-a-hex-sticker-for-rstats-packages/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today on twitter, Eric asked me this question
Looks terrific! What is your workflow for designing these? I may try one for the podcast soon
&amp;mdash; The R-Podcast (Eric) (@theRcast) January 31, 2019  Immediately after I replied I was using SketchApp, I realized he might be asking me about the actual &amp;ldquo;design workflow&amp;rdquo;. On this aspect, although I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m not the best person to say this but I did gain some experience through making the following 5 stickers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Arduino Chips with R</title>
      <link>https://zhuhao.org/post/connect-arduino-chips-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhuhao.org/post/connect-arduino-chips-with-r/</guid>
      <description>For now, the example below requires you to have a Mac or Linux computer. Windows support might come later.
 Sensors are fun. They are small electronic chips that can sense this world. Our smartphones have a bunch of sensors, like gyroscope and accelerometer, but you can also connect these sensors with either an Arduino or a Raspberry Pi. (In this post, I won&amp;rsquo;t talk about Raspberry Pi because although I have one Raspberry Pi at home, the only thing I did with that board so far is to get it out of box&amp;hellip; 😳)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start and Pause in a Streaming Plot using plotly</title>
      <link>https://zhuhao.org/post/start-and-pause-in-a-streaming-plot-using-plotly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhuhao.org/post/start-and-pause-in-a-streaming-plot-using-plotly/</guid>
      <description>plotly has a very nice example about how to making a streaming plot in R. When I was working on the arduino package, I need this feature because I want to create a plotting panel where data will be plotted once collected. So I used that example and quickly created a streaming app.
Here is the core part from the example
p &amp;lt;- plot_ly( y = c(rand(),rand(),rand()), type = &amp;#39;scatter&amp;#39;, mode = &amp;#39;lines&amp;#39;, line = list( color = &amp;#39;#25FEFD&amp;#39;, width = 3 ) ) %&amp;gt;% layout(yaxis = list(range = c(0,10))) output$plot &amp;lt;- renderPlotly(p) observeEvent(input$button, { while(TRUE){ Sys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in kableExtra 0.7.0</title>
      <link>https://zhuhao.org/post/what-s-new-in-kableextra-0-7-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhuhao.org/post/what-s-new-in-kableextra-0-7-0/</guid>
      <description>kableExtra 0.7.0 is on CRAN now. This update includes quite a few long-waited new features, including immediate display of HTML table in the Viewer panel and a remake for footnote (in replacement for add_footnote), and some important bug fixes.
New Features Live view of HTML table in RStudio HTML tables generated through kableExtra now has its own class and will be previewed in the Viewer panel when it’s printed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REDCap API and R Shiny</title>
      <link>https://zhuhao.org/post/2015-04-03-redcap-api-and-r-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhuhao.org/post/2015-04-03-redcap-api-and-r-shiny/</guid>
      <description>REDCap, as says on its website, is a &amp;ldquo;mature and secure web application for building and managing online surveys and databases&amp;rdquo;. It is used in many clinical researches as the database and the database management tool. One of the benefits of combining the usage of REDCap and R is that REDCap has an API (application programming interface), which can be used to easily export and import data into R. In this way, it can reduce the burden of data transformation and reduce possible human mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>